booktopia.com.au 2018-05-30

# Booktopia - Books, Online Books, #1 Australian online bookstore, Buy Discount Books, eBooks and DVDs from Australia and the world.

### Privacy Policy

Booktopia Pty Ltd ("Booktopia") respects your right to privacy and is committed to protecting your personal information. This Privacy Policy outlines how Booktopia Pty Ltd collects, uses and manages your personal information and incorporates compliance with the General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR) for EEA residents.

We respect the importance of your privacy and that you have a right to make your own choices about how your personal information is collected and used. We acknowledge that when you provide your personal information, you do so trusting Booktopia Pty Ltd and unless you directly give Booktopia Pty Ltd consent to do otherwise, Booktopia Pty Ltd will only collect and use your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

We give you:

  1. The right to be informed through this Privacy Policy, this website and our communications with you 
  2. The right of access to your information
  3. The right to rectification of your information
  4. The right to erasure of your information
  5. The right to restrict processing of your information
  6. The right to data portability should it be required
  7. The right to object to usage and storage of your information
  8. Rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling as relevant.

#### Collecting information about you

Except as stated in this Privacy Policy, Booktopia Pty Ltd will not collect or use your personal information without your consent. Booktopia Pty Ltd collects your personal information when you:

  * provide us your personal information and contact details;
  * order or purchase Booktopia products and/or services
  * enter your personal information on the Booktopia website or other Booktopia-owned properties;
  * participate in a Booktopia competition;
  * interact with us through social media (including Facebook and Twitter);
  * register on the Booktopia website/s
  * contact us; we may also keep a record of that contact.
  * We will only collect additional personal information with your consent.

#### Information you give us

We collect and store all the information you enter yourself into your Account and Email Newsletter Preference center, including personal information such as your name, addresses, phone number, email address; information about your orders; personal communications with us; and your newsletter preferences.

We collect and store any information you give to us when you contact us through our customer contact channels eg phone, email, chat, contact center, social media; that is relevant to you or us for the purposes of updating your information, or improving our service to you or offering you new products and services if relevant.

**Information from your use of our websites and services**

We collect and store information about your usage of our website when you browse and shop with us. This includes technical information such as your browser type; device type; IP address; length of time you are on part of a page, a page and the site, and other technical information.

Information collected and stored from browsing our websites is anonymous unless you are logged into your account and have visited us before, in which case this information is associated with your account by cookies that our servers place on your computer so that we can improve your browsing and shopping experience and offer further service and products to you onsite; by email (unless you have unsubscribed from such services); by retargeting services on other platforms via cookies eg social media; and other online properties not associated with us also via cookies.

We collect and store the above information in server logs and our database.

#### Booktopia Pty Ltd use of cookies

Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to your computer's hard disk for record keeping purposes. Most web browsers are set to accept cookies. Booktopia Pty Ltd uses cookies to make your use of our website and services as convenient as possible, such as by customising your web browser's access so that you can maintain your wishlist and shopping cart when you next visit the Booktopia Pty Ltd website. Cookies also enable Booktopia Pty Ltd to offer products and services for you on a more personalised basis.

Booktopia Pty Ltd uses web analytics tools, testing and other software that use cookies to improve your online experience, including the display of more relevant ads on other websites, based on your activities on your visits to the Booktopia website. If you do not wish to receive any cookies you may set your browser to refuse cookies, however not all the functionality of the Booktopia website may operate as expected.

#### Using and disclosing your personal information

Booktopia Pty Ltd's purpose in collecting your personal information is to provide you with:

  * the ability for you and Booktopia to complete or progress your order or transaction with us
  * information that interests you
  * information about events; and
  * special offers that are relevant to you

Booktopia Pty Ltd will not use or disclose any of your personal information without your consent, unless:

  * required by law;
  * Booktopia Pty Ltd believes it necessary to fulfil the above purposes or otherwise to provide you with services or products which you have requested; or
  * to protect the rights, property or personal safety of other users of the website, any member of the public or of Booktopia Pty Ltd.

In seeking to give you the most worthwhile experience in using the Booktopia website, your personal information may be used to send you advertisements about products and services that we think you are likely to be interested in.

Booktopia does not disclose your personal information to advertisers. We use the services of one or more trusted service providers located overseas to use and process personal information for the explicit purpose of fraud detection, transaction processing, or for providing a product or service to you, in accordance with applicable privacy and data protection laws. In order to operate the Booktopia website, fulfill the purposes set out above or otherwise deliver products or services, Booktopia will not otherwise disclose your personal information to other companies or third parties without your consent.

#### When Booktopia Pty Ltd will contact you

When you complete a purchase with Booktopia, you are presented with a comprehensive way to manage what marketing communications you wish to receive - if any - from Booktopia. Similarly, when you create an account or subscribe to Booktopia's newsletters, your preferences can be managed by you in their entirety.

Types of communications you may receive

  * updated information about the Booktopia website;
  * information about our products and services which may interest you; and
  * other information about upcoming events - such as discount promotions which may interest you.
  * Any communication enabled in the newsletter preferences area in your account

If you are receiving promotional information about Booktopia Pty Ltd and do not wish to receive this information any longer, you may remove your name from our list by visiting the Booktopia website and updating your newsletter preferences in your account. Please allow up to 3 business days for this request to be processed.

#### You can access the information Booktopia Pty Ltd keeps about you

If at any time you want to know what personal information Booktopia Pty Ltd holds about you, you can log into your Account and view the information you gave us. If you have further questions, you can contact us by phone.

#### How you can control the information collected by Booktopia

These are ways that you can control the information that may be collected and stored about you or your browsing activities.

**Your Account**

You can log into your account at any time and edit the information you have entered previously.

**Contact our call center**

You can contact our call center by any of the contact modes we offer to talk to a Customer Service representative about the information we have collected. We will delete information about your account or your entire account, except for information that is relevant to completing an order, or for legal or government purposes.

**Your Email Preference Centre**

You can log into your Email preference centre in Your Account and manage the types of communications you will receive from us that we have stored. You will receive advices about the status of any open orders until your order/s are complete.

**Block or Delete Cookies**

You can delete the cookies that our websites and associated services have placed in your browser. You should be aware however that your browsing or shopping experience may be reduced.

**Use Incognito or 'Safe Browsing' mode in your browser**

These modes allow you to browse the web without recording web pages and files in your browser. All cookies get deleted after you've closed all of your incognito windows and tabs and your bookmarks and settings are stored until you delete them.

#### Changing and updating the information Booktopia Pty Ltd has about you

If at any time you wish to change your personal information that is inaccurate or out of date, please contact our Customer Service team through your Message Center in your account, or by contacting our Customer Service team by phone and we will amend your personal information accordingly, or advise you how you can do this yourself within your account.

#### Deleting the information Booktopia Pty Ltd has about you or stopping any further advertising material or other communications

If you wish to have your personal information deleted, please let Booktopia know by contacting our customer service team, and we will take all reasonable steps to delete such information unless it must be kept for legal reasons. If you do not wish to receive further advertising, marketing or promotional information from Booktopia, please log into your account and change your electronic newsletter preferences, or by clicking the Unsubscribe link that is on every electronic marketing or promotional email that Booktopia sends to you.

To stop any further print direct-mail marketing communications, please contact our customer service team.

#### Storage and security of your personal information

Booktopia Pty Ltd will do everything reasonable and in its' power to keep secure the personal information which Booktopia Pty Ltd holds about you. Access to this information is restricted only to Booktopia Pty Ltd employees who have specific authorisation. Booktopia Pty Ltd also continually endeavours to improve security safeguards using the most stringent, industry-accepted online security and internal processes. That said, Booktopia will not be held responsible for events arising from unauthorised access to your personal information, but will do everything in our power to prevent it as a responsible, high-profile, Australian online retailer.

#### What to do if you have a problem or question

If Booktopia Pty Ltd becomes aware of any ongoing concerns or problems with the Booktopia Pty Ltd website, Booktopia Pty Ltd will work to address these concerns promptly. If you have any further queries relating to this Privacy Policy, or you have a problem or complaint, please contact Booktopia Pty Ltd by calling +612 9045 4394 Monday to Friday, 9am to 5pm Sydney time, except public holidays.

Enquiries in relation to the Privacy of residents in the EEA and the GDPR should be referred via the above methods with reference to the Data Protection Officer, Steven Traurig.

#### Future changes

Booktopia Pty Ltd is committed to being Australia's #1 online bookstore. This means that Booktopia Pty Ltd's business will continue to evolve and improve as new products, services and features are introduced. Accordingly, Booktopia Pty Ltd will review and update its policies as required. Booktopia Pty Ltd reserves the right to change its Privacy Policy at any time and notify you by posting an updated version of the policy on the Booktopia Pty Ltd website.

This amended Privacy Policy will apply whether or not Booktopia Pty Ltd has provided you specific notice of any changes or updates.

^ back to top

### Pricing Policy

All prices are listed in Australian dollars and are inclusive of GST. If placing an order from outside Australia you will be charged in your own currency at the conversion rate of your credit card company.

All prices on the Booktopia website are for orders placed via the website only. Orders placed by phone, fax (only for orders not with a Booktopia order number), in person at our office or by mail order will be charged the full RRP prices quoted on the website plus a $10 non-refundable administration fee as they will need to be hand processed by Booktopia staff.

All orders are subject to price and availability confirmation. If we cannot supply the product for the originally advertised price then Booktopia will do one of two things.

If the increase in price is marginal then Booktopia will absorb the increase and proceed with the order and adjust the price on the website after processing your order.

If the price is significantly more then we will not proceed until we have consulted with the customer via the message centre in your Booktopia account and outlined the options. The customer will not be charged for that item until Booktopia has been given confirmation to proceed with the new price. You have 48 hours to respond to the options given to you. If you respond after this time frame, you will be asked to place a new order through the website. If there are other titles on the order that are readily available then they will be automatically ordered, regardless of what percentage of the order they make up.

Booktopia are not obligated to sell a title at the listed price if we are not able to source it from our supplier at the time of ordering as prices may have changed in the interim. In all instances you will be contacted via the message centre in your Booktopia account if there is a change of price and Booktopia will endeavour to find an alternative edition for the same price or discuss the possibility of purchasing the same title at the new price.

We reserve the right to correct any pricing errors and we may cancel orders and refund your money because of genuine pricing errors (either because of unilateral mistake, or for any reason) up to the time you receive the goods.

^ back to top

### Online Abuse Policy

As an online bookstore with millions of books from around the world, there is always the likelihood to display and sell content, from an ever-changing landscape of publishers and authors, that can insult or offend someone or some groups - even the most seemingly-benign content. On our websites, we take the approach of selling entertainment and knowledge and enabling free speech and freedom of opinions and expression through books, but not at the expense of, or in specific danger to, our democratic and societal protections, rights and freedoms - particularly those of safety, security and religious, political or civil association. Google is famous for having a mantra of "Don't Be Evil" and we agree with that sentiment when it comes to books (unless you are Stephen King in which case context definitely counts, but that's the point!).

Booktopia itself has policies to address racism, bullying and hate within our company and we extend that for our websites, within the relevant Laws and what would be judged in an expected, reasonable manner. We do our best to swiftly assess and respond to reports of prohibited or illegal content on our website that falls foul of these Laws and principles, just as we so choose not to remove content that does not, according to our judgement and within the Law.

**What is Prohibited or Illegal content?**

The Office of the eSafety Commissioner of the Australian Government describes the following types of content that may be Prohibited or Illegal:

  * footage of real or simulated violence, criminal activity or accidents from video clips, games or films
  * sexually explicit content
  * images of child sexual abuse
  * content that advocates the doing of a terrorist act
  * content instructing or promoting crime or violence.

We expand this list to also include racism, bullying and harassment specifically and intently directed at people as well as other types of content. We have content and categories where lines definitely are drawn at different places within this list - including zero tolerance in many - in considered, educational or non-harming contexts and that we believe is a reasonable and acceptable way to behave in our society. 

What we are saying is that we do not automatically take content down just because you don't like or agree with it, but we do take content down that is reasonably or obviously harmful.

Good examples of content we do allow are books about topics that are widely accepted as educational resources, yet can be potentially offensive; for example most medical, religious and historical books would fit into this category (obviously not an exhaustive list) and there will always be a person or persons who demand that we take that content down, yet we do not. Examples of books we have taken down are bomb-making or other terrorism-related instruction manuals and explicitly-overt sexual, homophobic, bigoted or racist content specifically directed at a person, group or groups of people for the intent to cause harm. Intent and context of the book is important. Even so, we believe we can safely fulfil the wider reading needs in our society within the Law, yet without being necessarily or automatically held hostage to causes or people who would demand us to act in a way that would enforce their own views onto us and our readers. At the end of the day we take a non-radical, lawful and reasonable approach to what we sell and display on our websites and we do not tolerate Cyber Abuse.

**What is Cyber Abuse?**

The Office of the eSafety Commissioner of the Australian Government defines Cyber abuse as online behaviour which is reasonably likely to have a seriously threatening, intimidating, harassing or humiliating effect on a person. It is behaviour that threatens to hurt a person socially, psychologically or even physically. As above, we have a very low tolerance for this type of content and we welcome you to report it to us.

**Have something on our website to report?**

**_Please send an email to[abuse@booktopia.com.au](mailto:abuse@booktopia.com.au) We will consider your view and if we deem it appropriate to act, then we will do so._**

### Cover Images

The images on our website are intended as a guide only. As Booktopia does not keep every title in stock on site we are unable to guarantee the cover image that arrives from the supplier, will be that listed on the site. Publishers can have various cover designs for one ISBN so images can change without notification.

### Secure Shopping

Booktopia encrypts all personal information submitted to our server via industry-standard SSL.

### Returns Policy

We understand that from time-to-time you may need to return an item to us.

**Before returning any items please contact Booktopia Customer Service Team to discuss your reason for requiring a return and organise an approval to return an item to Booktopia.**

Before contacting Booktopia regarding a return please understand the following terms of business:

  1. Booktopia will not pay for postage if you are returning an item because you have changed your mind, or made a mistake in your ordering.
  2. If you have changed your mind, or made a mistake, we require notification within 2 business days of the recorded delivery date.
  3. If you received a faulty or damaged item, we require notification within 2 business days of the recorded delivery date.
  4. If the item you received is not what you ordered, we require notification within 5 business days of the recorded delivery date.
  5. Booktopia is NOT obligated to offer a store credit for products that are returned damaged to our Distribution Centre or never arrive. The Booktopia Distribution Centre address is: Unit E1, 3-29 Birnie Avenue, Lidcombe, NSW 2141. To qualify for a credit an item must be returned in perfect condition ready to be resold. Failure to package a returning item properly will undoubtedly result in no store credit and the product will be returned to the customer.
  6. A store credit issued for a return will be for the value of the returned item only. A store credit for a specific item does not cover the cost of postage.

For queries on Magazine Subscriptions please refer to Magazine Frequently Asked Questions.

^ back to top

### DVD & Blu-ray Returns

I have changed my mind or I made a mistake with my order

We are happy to **exchange** any unopened (still shrink-wrapped) DVD or Blu-ray within 14 days, provided the goods are returned in PRISTINE condition. 

Booktopia will not pay for postage if you are returning an item because you have changed your mind, or made a mistake in your ordering.

Booktopia will provide instructions for returning the item. If the product is damaged upon receipt in our warehouse, we are unable to accept the return and the item will be mailed back to you.

The item I ordered arrived damaged

Booktopia does pack every parcel with care to ensure it arrives at its destination in the same condition it left our warehouse. Unfortunately a small percentage of packages do arrive damaged due to mishandling by Australia Post employees and contractors as part of their standard parcel delivery program. As Australia Post offers Booktopia customers the most cost-effective and comprehensive delivery program we acknowledge that some parcels may arrive damaged and require replacing. 

If your item was damaged between leaving our warehouse and arriving at your delivery address, you must message Booktopia with your order number and the condition of your item/s within 2 days of the recorded delivery date.

Booktopia will replace the DVD or Blu-ray, depending on availability once the original disc is received back. Booktopia will provide instructions for returning the item. Refunds will not be processed unless a replacement cannot be provided. 

The item I ordered arrived faulty or didn't work as intended

If your item is found to be faulty, you must message Booktopia with your order number and the fault or problem of your item/s within 2 days of the recorded delivery date. 

Booktopia will replace the DVD or Blu-ray, depending on availability once the original disc is received back. Booktopia will provide instructions for returning the item. Refunds will not be processed unless a replacement cannot be provided. 

The item I received is not the item I ordered

If you receive an item that is not what you ordered, you must message Booktopia with your order number and the missing title and received title within 2 days of the recorded delivery date. 

Booktopia will replace the DVD or Blu-ray, depending on availability once the original disc is received back. Booktopia will provide instructions for returning the item. Refunds will not be processed unless a replacement cannot be provided. 

^ back to top
